I'm a teacher and a practitioner
أنا معلم وممارس
of civics in America.
للتربية المدنية في الولايات المتحدة.
Now, I will kindly ask those of you who have just fallen asleep
الآن، أطلب من الذين قد ناموا للتو
to please wake up. (Laughter)
رجاء أن يستيقظوا. (ضحك)
Why is it that the very word "civics"
لم تحمل كلمة التربية المدنية
has such a soporific, even a narcoleptic effect
ذلك التأثير المنوم أو المخدر حتى
on us?
علينا؟
I think it's because the very word signifies something
باعتقادي هذه الكلمة تدل على شيء معين
exceedingly virtuous, exceedingly important,
قوي جدا، مهم جدا،
and exceedingly boring.
وممل جدا.
Well, I think it's the responsibility of people like us,
حسنا، أعتقد أن هذه مسؤولية أشخاص مثلنا،
people who show up for gatherings like this
الأشخاص الذين يحضرون لتجمعات مثل هذه
in person or online, in any way we can,
شخصيا أوعن طريق الانترنت، بأي طريقة كانت،
to make civics sexy again,
لكي نجعل التربية المدنية مثيرة مرة أخرى،
as sexy as it was during the American Revolution,
مثيرة مثلما كانت خلال الثورة الأمريكية،
as sexy as it was during the Civil Rights Movement.
مثيرة مثلما كانت خلال الحراك من أجل الحقوق المدنية.
And I believe the way we make civics sexy again
وباعتقادي فإن الطريقة التي يمكن بها جعل التربية المدنية مثيرة مجددا
is to make explicitly about the teaching of power.
هو أن نجهر بما يتعلق بتعليم القوة.
The way we do that, I believe,
الطريقة التي علينا أن نتبعها، باعتقادي
is at the level of the city.
هي على مستوى المدينة.
This is what I want to talk about today,
وهذا ما أريد أن أتحدث عنه اليوم،
and I want to start by defining some terms
وأريد أن أبدأ بتعريف بعض المصطلحات
and then I want to describe the scale
بعدها أريد أن أصف مدى
of the problem I think we face
المشكل الذي نواجهه
and then suggest the ways that I believe cities
وبعد ذلك أقترح طرقا باعتقادي أن المدن
can be the seat of the solution.
يمكنها أن تكون موضعا للحل.
So let me start with some definitions.
إذا دعوني أبدأ ببعض التعاريف.
By civics, I simply mean the art
ما أعنيه بالتربية المدنية، ببساطة هي فن
of being a pro-social, problem-solving contributor
كون المرء مواليا اجتماعيا، مشاركا في إيجاد الحلول
in a self-governing community.
في مجتمع يحكم ذاته بذاته.
Civics is the art of citizenship,
التربية المدنية هي فن المواطنة،
what Bill Gates Sr. calls simply
ما يسميه بيل غيتس ببساطة
showing up for life,
الظهور في الحياة،
and it encompasses three things:
والذي يشمل ثلاثة أمور:
a foundation of values,
أساس من القيم،
an understanding of the systems that make the world go round,
فهم جيد للنظم التي تسير العالم،
and a set of skills
ومجموعة من المهارات
that allow you to pursue goals
التي تمكنك من السعي وراء الأهداف
and to have others join in that pursuit.
وجعل الآخرين ينضمون إليك في هذا السعي.
And that brings me to my definition of power,
وهذا يحيلني إلى تعريف القوة،
which is simply this:
وهو ببساطة:
the capacity to make others do
القدرة على جعل الآخرين يقومون
what you would have them do.
بما تريدهم أن يقوموا به.
It sounds menacing, doesn't it?
تبدو نبرة التهديد في هذا أليس كذلك؟
We don't like to talk about power.
لا نحب أن نتحدث عن القوة.
We find it scary. We find it somehow evil.
إذ تبدو مخيفة، وأحيانا شريرة.
We feel uncomfortable naming it.
لا نشعر بالارتياح ونحن نذكرها.
In the culture and mythology of democracy,
في ثقافة وأسطورة الديمقراطية،
power resides with the people.
فإن القوة تكمن في الناس.
Period. End of story.
نقطة. انتهى.
Any further inquiry not necessary
كل نقاش زائد في هذا الموضوع ليس ضروريا
and not really that welcome.
وليس مرحبا به أصلا.
Power has a negative moral valence.
للقوة معنى ثقافي سلبي.
It sounds Machiavellian inherently.
إذ يبدو أنها إرث ميكيافيلي.
It seems inherently evil.
تبدو وكأنها شريرة بالفطرة.
But in fact power is no more inherently good or evil
لكن القوة في الواقع ليست شريرة أو خيرة بالفطرة
than fire or physics.
أكثر من النار أو الفيزياء.
It just is.
هي ما هي عليه فحسب.
And power governs
والقوة تتحكم
how any form of government operates,
في كيفية عمل أي شكل من الحكومات،
whether a democracy or a dictatorship.
سواء كانت ديمقراطية أو ديكتاتورية.
And the problem we face today, here in America in particular,
والمشكل الذي نواجهه اليوم، خصوصا هنا في الولايات المتحدة،
but all around the world,
بل في العالم أجمع،
is that far too many people are profoundly illiterate
أن أغلبية الناس يعانون من أمية شديدة
in power —
فيما يتعلق بالقوة -
what it is, who has it,
ماهيتها، من يمتلكها
how it operates, how it flows,
كيف تعمل؛ كيف تسري،
what part of it is visible, what part of it is not,
ما الجزء الظاهر منها، ما الجزء الخفي،
why some people have it, why that's compounded.
لم يمتلكها البعض، لم تتضخم.
And as a result of this illiteracy,
وكنتيجة لهذه الأمية،
those few who do understand
فإن الناس القلائل الذين يفهمون
how power operates in civic life,
كيف تعمل القوة في الحياة المدنية،
those who understand
أولئك الذين يفهمون
how a bill becomes a law, yes,
كيف لفاتورة أن تصبح قانونا، أجل،
but also how a friendship becomes a subsidy,
وكذلك كيف لصداقة أن تصبح مصلحة،
or how a bias becomes a policy,
أو كيف لانحياز أن يصبح سياسة،
or how a slogan becomes a movement,
أو كيف لشعار أن يصبح حراكا،
the people who understand those things
فالناس الذين يفهمون هذه الأمور
wield disproportionate influence,
يوازنون التأثير المختل،
and they're perfectly happy
ويكونون سعداء للغاية
to fill the vacuum created by the ignorance
لملء الفراغ الناجم عن جهل
of the great majority.
الغالبية العظمى.
This is why it is so fundamental for us right now
لذلك فمن الضروري بالنسبة لنا الآن
to grab hold of this idea of power
أن نأخذ فكرة القوة هذه
and to democratize it.
ونقوم بدمقرطتها.
One of the things that is so profoundly exciting
من الأمور الأكثر إثارة
and challenging about this moment
وتحديا بخصوص هذا الحراك
is that as a result of this power illiteracy
أنه وكنتيجة عن هذا الجهل بالقوة
that is so pervasive,
الشديد جدا،
there is a concentration
هناك تركيز
of knowledge, of understanding, of clout.
للعلم وللفهم وللنفوذ
I mean, think about it:
أعني، فكروا بالأمر:
How does a friendship become a subsidy?
كيف لصداقة أن تصبح مصلحة؟
Seamlessly,
وبدون أدنى وجه تشابه،
when a senior government official decides
حين يقرر مسؤول حكومي رفيع
to leave government and become a lobbyist
أن يترك الحكومة لينضم إلى مجموعة ضغط
for a private interest
ذات أهداف خاصة
and convert his or her relationships into capital
فيحول علاقاته إلى رأس مال
for their new masters.
لصالح رؤسائه الجدد.
How does a bias become a policy?
كيف لانحياز أن يصبح سياسة؟
Insidiously, just the way that
بكل دهاء، بنفس الطريقة
stop-and-frisk, for instance,
مثلا كيف أصبح قانون أوقف- و- فتش
became over time a bureaucratic numbers game.
مع مرور الزمن لعبة أرقام بيروقراطية.
How does a slogan become a movement?
كيف لشعار أن يصبح حراكا؟
Virally, in the way that the Tea Party, for instance,
بشكل سريع، بنفس الطريقة التي استطاع "حزب الشاي" مثلا،
was able to take the "Don't Tread on Me" flag
أن يأخذ علم" لا تدس عليّ"
from the American Revolution,
من الثورة الأمريكية،
or how, on the other side,
أو كيف، بالمقابل،
a band of activists could take a magazine headline,
لمجموعة من النشطاء أن تأخذ عنوان مجلة،
"Occupy Wall Street,"
"احتلوا وول ستريت"،
and turn that into a global meme and movement.
لتحوله إلى شعار وحراك عالميين.
The thing is, though, most people
الفكرة هنا، بالمقابل، أن معظم الناس
aren't looking for and don't want to see these realities.
لا يبحثون ولا يريدون رؤية هذه الحقائق.
So much of this ignorance, this civic illiteracy,
معظم هذا الجهل والأمية المدنية؛
is willful.
هو أمر متعمد.
There are some millennials, for instance,
هناك من جيل هذه الألفية، مثلا،
who think the whole business is just sordid.
من يعتقد أن هذا الأمر برمته مجرد تفاهة.
They don't want to have anything to do with politics.
لا يريدون أن ينخرطوا في أي شيء له علاقة بالسياسة.
They'd rather just opt out
يفضلون الانسحاب
and engage in volunteerism.
والانخراط في العمل التطوعي.
There are some techies out there
هناك العديد من محبي التكنولوجيا
who believe that the cure-all
من يظنون أن الحل الشافي
for any power imbalance or power abuse
للخلل في توازن القوة أو سوء استخدام السلطة
is simply more data,
يكمن في جمع المزيد من البيانات،
more transparency.
في المزيد من الشفافية.
There are some on the left who think power resides
هناك من هم في اليسار ممن يعتقدون أن القوة توجد
only with corporations,
فقط مع الشركات الكبرى،
and some on the right who think power
ومن هم في اليمين من يعتقدون أن القوة
resides only with government,
توجد فقط مع الحكومات،
each side blinded by their selective outrage.
وقد عميت كل فرقة بغضبها الانتقائي.
There are the naive who believe that
وهناك السذج الذين يؤمنون
good things just happen
أن الأشياء الجيدة تحدث هكذا
and the cynical who believe that bad things just happen,
وهناك الساخرون الذين يؤمنون أن الأشياء السلبية تحدث هكذا،
the fortunate and unfortunate alike
والمحظوظون والتعساء بالمقابل
who think that their lot is simply what they deserve
من يظنون أن حظهم ببساطة هو ما يستحقونه
rather than the eminently alterable result
عوضا عن نتيجة واضحة قابلة للتغيير
of a prior arrangement, an inherited allocation,
لترتيب مسبق، أو توزيع موروث
of power.
للقوة.
As a result of all of this creeping fatalism in public life,
ونتيجة لكل هذه الحتمية الزاحفة في الحياة العامة،
we here, particularly in America today,
لدينا هنا، بالتحديد في الولايات المتحدة اليوم،
have depressingly low levels
مستويات متدنية بشكل مقلق
of civic knowledge, civic engagement, participation,
للمعرفة المدنية، الانخراط المدني، للمشاركة
awareness.
والوعي.
The whole business of politics has been
قضية السياسة هذه برمتها
effectively subcontracted out to a band of professionals,
قد تم تفويضها تعاقديا لعصابة من المهنيين،
money people, outreach people,
أصحاب الأموال، أصحاب الوعي،
message people, research people.
أصحاب الخطب، أصحاب الأبحاث.
The rest of us are meant to feel like amateurs
بالنسبة للبقية منا، فقد قُدِّرَ لنا أن نكون مثل الهواة
in the sense of suckers.
بمعنى المتلصصين.
We become demotivated to learn more
أصبحنا محبطين لنتعلم أكثر
about how things work.
عن كيفية عمل الأشياء.
We begin to opt out.
بدأنا بالانسحاب.
Well, this problem, this challenge,
حسنا، هذا المشكل، هذا التحدي،
is a thing that we must now confront,
هو أمر علينا مواجهته الآن،
and I believe that when you have
وأعتقد أنه حين يكون لديك
this kind of disengagement, this willful ignorance,
هذا النوع من التنصل، من الجهل المتعمد،
it becomes both a cause and a consequence
فإن الأمر يصبح سببا ونتيجة
of this concentration of opportunity
لتمركز فرص
of wealth and clout that I was describing a moment ago,
الغنى والنفوذ الذين كنت أتحدث عنهما قبل قليل،
this profound civic inequality.
عن ذلك التفاوت العميق في التربية المدنية.
This is why it is so important in our time right now
لذلك فإنه من المهم جدا في زمننا الآن
to reimagine civics as the teaching of power.
أن نعيد تصور التربية المدنية على أساس أنها تعليم للقوة.
Perhaps it's never been more important
ربما لم يكن الأمر قط أكثر أهمية
at any time in our lifetimes.
في أي وقت من حياتنا.
If people don't learn power,
إن لم يتعلم الناس شيئا عن السلطة،
people don't wake up,
إن لم يستيقظوا،
and if they don't wake up,
وإن لم يستيقظوا،
they get left out.
سيتم التخلي عنهم.
Now, part of the art of practicing power
الآن، كجزء من فن ممارسة السلطة
means being awake and having a voice,
يعني أن نكون مستيقظين وذوي رأي،
but it also is about having an arena
ولكن أيضا أن يكون لدينا مجال
where you can plausibly practice deciding.
حيث يمكننا أن نمارس اتخاذ القرار بشكل معقول.
All of civics boils down to the simple question
تتلخص التربية المدنية كلها في سؤال بسيط
of who decides,
والذي هو: من يقرر
and you have to play that out
وعليك أن تلعب بهذا السؤال
in a place, in an arena.
في مكان ما، في مجال ما.
And this brings me to the third point that I want to make today,
وهذا يحيلني إلى النقطة الثالثة التي أريد أن أناقشها اليوم،
which is simply that there is no better arena
والتي ببساطة عن أنه لا مجال أفضل
in our time for the practicing of power
لممارسة السلطة في وقتنا الحالي
than the city.
من المدينة.
Think about the city where you live,
فكر بالمدينة التي تعيش فيها،
where you're from.
التي تنتمي إليها.
Think about a problem in the common life of your city.
فكر في مشكل في الحياة العامة في المدينة.
It can be something small,
قد يكون أمرا صغيرا،
like where a street lamp should go,
مثلا أين يمكن وضع إضاءة الشارع،
or something medium like
أو أمرا ذا أهمية متوسطة،
which library should have its hours extended or cut,
مثلا ما هي المكتبة التي يجب زيادة أوقات عملها أو تقليلها،
or maybe something bigger,
أو ربما أمرا أكبر،
like whether a dilapidated waterfront should be
إن كان يجب تحويل واجهة مائية متهالكة
turned into a highway or a greenway,
إلى طريق سريع أو مسار أخضر،
or whether all the businesses in your town
أو إن كان يجب على كل الشركات في مدينتك
should be required to pay a living wage.
أن تدفع الحد الأدنى للأجور.
Think about the change that you want in your city,
فكر بالتغيير الذي تريد أن تراه في مدينتك،
and then think about how you would get it,
ثم فكر في كيفية الوصول إليه،
how you would make it happen.
كيف يمكن أن تحوله إلى حقيقة.
Take an inventory of all the forms of power
اعمل جرذا لكل أشكال السلطة
that are at play in your city's situation:
التي تعمل على الساحة في مدينتك:
money, of course, people, yes,
المال، بطبيعة الحال والناس، أجل،
ideas, information, misinformation,
الأفكار والمعلومات والمعلومات الخاطئة،
the threat of force, the force of norms.
وتهديد القوة وقوة المعايير.
All of these form of power are at play.
كل أشكال السلطة هذه تلعب دورا.
Now think about how you would activate
الآن فكر كيف يمكنك أن تنشط
or perhaps neutralize these various forms of power.
أو ربما تحيد أشكال السلطة المختلفة هذه.
This is not some Game of Thrones
ليست هذه أسئلة
empire-level set of questions.
لمسلسل Game of Thrones.
These are questions that play out
هذه هي الأسئلة التي تتحكم بقواعد اللعبة
in every single place on the planet.
في كل مكان على سطح الكوكب.
I'll just tell you quickly about two stories
سأخبركم بسرعة عن قصتين
drawn from recent headlines.
مستقاة من أخبار حديثة.
In Boulder, Colorado,
في بولدر في كولورادو،
voters not too long ago approved a process
وافق الناخبون منذ زمن ليس ببعيد على مشروع
to replace the private power company,
لاستبدال شركة الكهرباء الخاصة،
literally the power company, the electric company Xcel,
بالتحديد شركة الكهرباء، شركة إكسل الكهربائية،
with a publicly owned utility
بمصنع مملوك للدولة
that would forego profits
من شأنه أن يحقق أرباحا بسرعة
and attend far more to climate change.
وأن يحقق تقدما فيما يخص التغير المناخي،
Well, Xcel fought back,
حسنا، دافعت إكسل عن نفسها،
and Xcel has now put in play a ballot measure
ووضعت على الطاولة مقياسا للاقتراح
that would undermine or undo
من شأنه أن يقوض أو يلغي
this municipalization.
قرار منح السلطة للبلدية.
And so the citizen activists in Boulder who have been pushing this
إذا فقد كان على النشطاء المواطنين في بولدر المدافعين عن هذا القرار
now literally have to fight the power
أن يحاربوا هذه السلطة بما في الكلمة من معنى
in order to fight for power.
لكي يحاربوا من أجل السلطة.
In Tuscaloosa, at the University of Alabama,
في توكالوسا، في جامعة آلاباما،
there's an organization on campus
هناك تنظيم في الحرم الجامعي
called, kind of menacingly, the Machine,
يسمى، بشكل تهديدي نوعا ما، "ذ ماشين"،
and it draws from largely white sororities
والذي يتشكل بشكل كبير من جمعيات النساء البيض،
and fraternities on campus,
والأخويات في الحرم،
and for decades, the Machine has dominated
ولعقود، فقد سيطرت ذ ماشين
student government elections.
على انتخابات حكومات الطلبة.
Well now, recently, the Machine
حسنا الآن، مؤخرا، بدأت ذ ماشين
has started to get involved
في الانخراط
in actual city politics,
في السياسات الحقيقية للمدينة،
and they've engineered the election
وقد هندسوا انتخاب
of a former Machine member,
أحد أعضاء ذ ماشين السابقين،
a young, pro-business recent graduate
وهو خريج جديد، شاب موال لهم
to the Tuscaloosa city school board.
في مجلس التعليم في مدينة توسكالوسا.
Now, as I say, these are just two examples
الآن، كما أقول، هذان مثالان فقط
drawn almost at random from the headlines.
مستوحيان عشوائيا من الأخبار.
Every day, there are thousands more like them.
في كل يوم، هناك الآلاف من هذه الأمثلة.
And you may like or dislike
وقد تعجبكم المجهودات
the efforts I'm describing here
التي أصفها هنا
in Boulder or in Tuscaloosa,
في بولدر أو توسكالوزا أو قد لا تعجبكم،
but you cannot help but admire
لكن لن يسعكم إلى أن تعجبوا
the power literacy of the players involved,
بقوة معرفة اللاعبين المنخرطين في هذا الأمر،
their skill.
ومهارتهم.
You cannot help but reckon with and recognize
لن يسعكم إلى أن تحسبوا لهم ألف حساب وتعترفوا
the command they have
بسيطرتهم
of the elemental questions
على القضايا الأساسية
of civic power —
للسلطة المدنية--
what objective, what strategy, what tactics,
ما هو الهدف وما هي الاستراتيجية، وما هي الخطوات،
what is the terrain, who are your enemies,
وما هو ملعبك ومن هم أعداؤك،
who are your allies?
ومن هم أنصارك؟
Now I want you to return
الآن أريدكم أن تعودوا
to thinking about that problem or that opportunity
لتفكروا في ذلك المشكل أو تلك الفرصة
or that challenge in your city,
أو ذلك التحدي الذي يواجه مدينتك،
and the thing it was that you want to fix
وذلك الأمر الذي تريد أن تصلحه
or create in your city,
أو تخلقه داخل مدينتك،
and ask yourself,
وتسأل نفسك،
do you have command of these elemental questions of power?
هل لديك أي سلطة على قضايا القوة الأساسية؟
Could you put into practice effectively
هل يمكنك أن تطبق بطريقة فعالة
what it is that you know?
الأمور التي تعرفها؟
This is the challenge and the opportunity for us.
هذا هو التحدي وكذلك الفرصة التي توجد أمامنا.
We live in a time right now
نعيش الآن
where in spite of globalization
حيث على الرغم من وجود العولمة
or perhaps because of globalization,
أو ربما بسبب العولمة،
all citizenship is ever more resonantly,
فإن كل الجنسيات أصبحت أكثر من أي وقت مضى
powerfully local.
محلية بشكل قوي ومدو.
Indeed, power in our time is flowing
وبالفعل فإن السلطة تتسلل في زمننا
ever faster to the city.
نحو المدينة بشكل متسارع.
Here in the United States, the national government
هنا في الولايات المتحدة فقد ربطت الحكومة الوطنية
has tied itself up in partisan knots.
نفسها بعقد من الأنصار.
Civic imagination and innovation and creativity
والآن فإن المخيلة المدنية والابتكار والإبداع
are emerging from local ecosystems now
تنبثق من النظام المحلي
and radiating outward,
فتشع نحو الخارج،
and this great innovation,
وهذا الابتكار العظيم،
this great wave
هذه الموجة العظيمة
of localism that's now arriving,
من إبراز الخاصية المحلية التي تتجه إلينا،
and you see it in how people eat
التي ترونها في كيفية أكل الناس
and work and share and buy and move
في عملهم، تقاسمهم، شرائهم وحركتهم
and live their everyday lives,
وكيفية عيشهم لحياتهم اليومية،
this isn't some precious parochialism,
ليس هذا ضربا من تضييق الأمل الثمين،
this isn't some retreat into insularity, no.
ليس هذا نوعا من العودة إلى العزلة، لا.
This is emergent.
هذا انبثاق.
The localism of our time is networked powerfully.
خاصية المحلية في زمننا مرتبطة ببعضها بقوة.
And so, for instance,
وبالتالي، على سبيل المثال،
consider the ways that strategies
فلننظر إلى الطرق التي انتشرت بها استراتيجيات
for making cities more bike-friendly
جعل المدن صديقة للدراجات
have spread so rapidly from Copenhagen
بسرعة كبيرة من كوبنهاغن
to New York to Austin to Boston to Seattle.
إلى نيويورك إلى أوستن إلى سياتل.
Think about how experiments in participatory budgeting,
فكر بتجارب وضع ميزانية تشاركية،
where everyday citizens get a chance
حيث يتسنى للمواطنين كل يوم
to allocate and decide upon
أن يخصصوا ويقرروا بشأن
the allocation of city funds.
توزيع أموال المدينة.
Those experiments have spread from Porto Alegre, Brazil
انتشرت هذه التجارب من بورتي اليغر، في البرازيل
to here in New York City, to the wards of Chicago.
لتصل إلى مدينة نيويورك إلى تخوم شيكاغو.
Migrant workers from Rome to Los Angeles
يقوم العمال المهاجرون من روما إلى لوس أنجلوس
and many cities between
ومدن أخرى مجاورة
are now organizing to stage strikes
بتنظيم إضرابات مرحلية
to remind the people who live in their cities
ليذكروا الناس الذين يعيشون في مدنهم
what a day without immigrants would look like.
كيف سيبدو يومهم بدون عمل المهاجرين.
In China, all across that country,
في الصين، وفي أرجاء البلاد كلها،
members of the New Citizens' Movement
بدأ أعضاء من حركة “المواطنون الجدد"
are beginning to activate and organize
في الحراك والتنظيم
to fight official corruption and graft,
ليواجهوا الفساد والكسب غير المشروع للمسؤولين،
and they're drawing the ire of officials there,
وهم بذلك قد أثاروا غضب المسؤولين هناك،
but they're also drawing the attention
وكذا اهتمام
of anti-corruption activists all around the world.
النشطاء المناهضين للفساد في جميع أنحاء العالم.
In Seattle, where I'm from,
في سياتل، التي أنتمي إليها،
we've become part of a great global array of cities
فقد أصبحنا ننتمي لمجموعة من المدن العالمية الكبرى
that are now working together
التي تعمل الآن سوية
bypassing government altogether,
متجاوزين الحكومات بأكملها،
national government altogether,
الحكومات الوطنية بمجملها،
in order to try to meet the carbon reduction goals
بهدف محاولة الوصول إلى الأهداف المتعلقة بتخفيض الكربون
of the Kyoto Protocol.
الخاص ببروتوكول كيوتو.
All of these citizens, united,
كل أولئك المواطنين، الموحدون،
are forming a web,
قد شكلوا شبكة،
a great archipelago of power
أرخبيلا من القوة
that allows us to bypass
الذي سيمكننا من تجاوز
brokenness and monopolies of control.
الخلل واحتكار السلطة.
And our task now is to accelerate this work.
مهمتنا الآن هي تسريع هذه العملية.
Our task now is to bring more and more people
مهمتنا اليوم هو إشراك العديد والعديد من الناس
into the fold of this work.
في هذا العمل.
That's why my organization, Citizen University,
لذلك، فإن منظمتي، جامعة المواطن،
has undertaken a project now
منكبة الآن على مشروع
to create an everyman's curriculum
يسعى لخلق منهج لكل فرد
in civic power.
فيما يخص القوة المدنية.
And this curriculum starts with this triad
ويبدأ هذا المنهج بهذه الثلاثية
that I described earlier of values,
التي وصفتها سابقا وهي القيم،
systems and skills.
النظم والمهارات.
And what I'd like to do is to invite all of you
وما أريد القيام به هو أن أدعوكم جميعا
to help create this curriculum
أن تساهموا في خلق هذا المنهج
with the stories and the experiences
عن طريق القصص والتجارب
and the challenges that each of you lives and faces,
والتحديات التي يعيشها ويواجهها كل منكم،
to create something powerfully collective.
لنخلق شيئا جماعيا جبارا.
And I want to invite you in particular to try
وأريد أن أدعوكم بالخصوص أن تحاولوا
a simple exercise drawn
القيام بتمرين بسيط مستوحى
from the early frameworks of this curriculum.
من الأطر الأولية لهذا المنهج.
I want you to write a narrative,
أريدكم أن تكتبوا نصا،
a narrative from the future of your city,
نصا عن مستقبل مدينتكم،
and you can date it, set it out one year from now,
يمكن أن تضعوا تاريخا له، اجعلوه خلال سنة من الآن،
five years from now, a decade from now,
في غضون خمس سنوات أو عقد من الآن،
a generation from now,
أو جيل من الآن.
and write it as a case study looking back,
واكتبوه على شكل دراسة حالة تنظر إلى الوراء،
looking back at the change
عودوا بنظركم إلى التغيير
that you wanted in your city,
الذي تريدونه لمدينتكم،
looking back at the cause that you were championing,
عودوا بنظركم إلى القضية التي كنتم تناصرون،
and describing the ways that that change
وصفوا الطرق التي وصل بها ذلك التغيير
and that cause came, in fact, to succeed.
وتلك القضية، إلى نجاح حقيقي.
Describe the values
صفوا القيم
of your fellow citizens that you activated,
التي يتحلى بها مواطنوكم الذين حشدتم،
and the sense of moral purpose that you were able to stir.
ومعنى الهدف الأخلاقي الذي تمكنتم من شحذه.
Recount all the different ways
أعيدوا حساب كل الطرق المختلفة
that you engaged the systems of government,
التي عملتم بها لإشراك نظم الحكومات،
of the marketplace,
والسوق،
of social institutions, of faith organizations,
والمؤسسات الاجتماعية، والمنظمات العقدية،
of the media.
والإعلام.
Catalog all the skills you had to deploy,
اعرضوا كل المهارات التي نشرتم،
how to negotiate, how to advocate,
حول كيفية التفاوض، والدفاع،
how to frame issues,
كيفية تأطير القضايا،
how to navigate diversity in conflict,
كيفية الإبحار في التنوع في حالة النزاع،
all those skills that enabled you
كل تلك المهارات التي مكنتكم
to bring folks on board
من إشراك أشخاص في التسيير
and to overcome resistance.
وتجاوز شعور المقاومة لديهم.
What you'll be doing when you write that narrative
ما ستقومون به حين ستكتبون ذلك النص
is you'll be discovering how to read power,
أنكم ستكتشفون كيف يمكنكم قراءة السلطة،
and in the process, how to write power.
وفي ذلك الخضم، كيفية كتابة السلطة.
So share what you write,
لذا فلتتقاسموا ما تكتبون،
do you what you write,
ولتقوموا بما تكتبون،
and then share what you do.
وبعدها تقاسموا ما تفعلون.
I invite you to literally share
أدعوكم لتتقاسموا بكل ما في الكلمة من معنى
the narratives that you create
النصوص التي تخلقونها
on our Facebook page for Citizen University.
على صفحتنا على الفيسبوك Citizen University.
But even beyond that, it's in the conversations
ولكن ما أبعد من ذلك، هو تلك المحادثات
that we have today
التي نتقاسمها اليوم
all around the world in the simultaneous gatherings
في كل أنحاء العالم في تجمعاتنا المتزامنة
that are happening on this topic at this moment,
والتي تدور حول هذا الموضوع في هذه اللحظة،
and to think about how we can become
لنفكر كيف يمكننا أن نصبح
one another's teachers and students in power.
معلمين وتلاميذا لبعضنا البعض فيما يتعلق بالسلطة.
If we do that, then together
إذا قمنا بهذا، حينها جميعا
we can make civics sexy again.
يمكننا أن نجعل التربية المدنية مثيرة مجددا.
Together, we can democratize democracy
جميعا يمكننا دمقرطة الديمقراطية
and make it safe again for amateurs.
ونجعلها آمنة مجددا بالنسبة للهواة.
Together, we can create a great network of city
جميعا، يمكننا أن نخلق رابطة عظيمة للمدينة
that will be the most powerful collective laboratory
والتي ستصبح أقوى مختبر جماعي
for self-government this planet has ever seen.
للتسيير الذاتي، كما لم يعرفه الكون من قبل.
We have the power to do that.
لدينا القوة للقيام بهذا.
Thank you very much.
شكرا جزيلا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)